This is a true story.
The Big Short is a comedy, drama film directed by Adam McKay.
The men who made millions from a global economic meltdown.
Mark Baum, played by Steve Carell.
Michael Burry, played by Christian Bale.
Jared Vennett, played by Ryan Gosling.
Ben Rickert, played by Brad Pitt.
Cynthia Baum, played by Marisa Tomei.
Georgia Hale, played by Melissa Leo.
The Big Short is a 2015 American biographical comedy drama film directed by
Adam McKay from a screenplay by McKay and Charles Randolph.
Based on the 2010 book of the same name by Michael Lewis, it depicts how the 2008
financial crisis was triggered by the United States housing bubble.
The film stars Christian Bale, Steve Carell, Ryan Gosling, and Brad Pitt, with John Magaro, Finn
Wittrock, Hamish Linklater, Rafe Spall, Jeremy Strong, and Marisa Tomei in supporting roles.
The Big Short began a limited release in the United States on December 11, 2015,
followed by a wide release on December 23 by Paramount Pictures.
A critical and commercial success, the film grossed $133 million on a $50 million budget and received acclaim for the
performances of the cast (particularly those of Bale and Carell), McKay's direction, editing, and the screenplay.
The film won the Academy Award for Best Adapted Screenplay in addition to nominations for Best
Picture, Best Director, Best Supporting Actor (Bale), and Best Film Editing.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
bank, fraud, wall street, biography.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.